让我们做一个不同类型的函数。
Let's do a different type of function.
摆脱这些东西并专注于，如果我们宁愿而不是
Get rid of this stuff and focus on, what if we would rather instead of
通过运行两者然后组合结果来组合函数，
combining functions by running both and then combining the results,
这是串联因素背后的一种正常直觉。
which is kind of the normal intuition behind concatenating factors.
我们可以做的是像函数组合这样的组合作为串联。
We can do is make a composition like function composition as concatenation.
所以我有一件事情，我想去上边惊呼，对吧？
So I have like a thing where I want to go to upper and exclaim, right?
我只想喜欢折叠地图，我想合并。
And I just wanna like fold map that and I want to combine.
我希望它同时做这两件事。
I want it to do both of those things.
所以让我们这样做。
So let's do that.
为此，我们将制作一种名为 Endo 的类型。
And for that, we're gonna make a type called Endo.
如果有人早些时候看到我的 Snoop Dogg 幻灯片，
That was if anybody saw my Snoop Dogg slide earlier,
但是 [笑] 我们有 Endo.empty。
but [LAUGH] we have Endo.empty.
好吧，那会做什么呢？
All right, so what would that do?
这将为我提供一个函数，当我使用字符串 hello 运行它时，
That would provide me a function that when I run it with my string hello,
我应该得到 HELLO 所有的资本。
I should get HELLO all capital.
它有一个先操作然后解释。
It's got a first to operate and then explain.
它只会运行一系列功能和新组合。
It;s just gonna run through a pipeline of functions and new composition.
现在，它被称为 Endo 的原因很奇怪是因为
Now, the reason it's called Endo which is weird is because
这仅适用于自同态，这意味着它仅适用于类型 a 到 a，
this only works with endomorphisms meaning it only works from types a to a,
在这种情况下，字符串到字符串或任务到任务或
in this case string to string or task to task or
无论它有什么，它都有与输出相同类型的输入。
whatever to whatever it has this have the same type of input as output.
原因是因为现在我们知道我们可以
And the reason for that is because now we know we can just
编写它们，而不会遇到它们不编写的任何类型问题 [笑]。
compose them without running into any type problems where they don't compose [LAUGH].
所以这只是有点绕开说，好吧，如果他们总是那种类型，相同
So this just kinda skirts that and says, okay, if they're always the type, same
输入的类型是输出，我们只需将其穿线，它们将始终组成。
type of input is output, we'll just thread it through and they'll always compose.
让我们写远藤。
Let's write Endo.
嘟嘟嘟嘟嘟嘟。
Doo doo doo doo doo doo.
如果我们有时间，我们会再谈一谈。
And if we have time we'll talk about one more.
不过暂时应该没问题。
But this should be fine for now.
所以我们有了 Endo，让我们不用担心映射链和任何事情。
So we have Endo, let's not worry about mapping chain and anything.
实际上，你不能映射Endo，endo是一个字符串到字符串或一天或一天的函数
In fact, you can't map Endo, endo is a function from string to string or a day or
进入 int 或任何它总是相同的类型。
into int or whatever it's always the same type.
如果我尝试使用地图更改第二种类型，如果我在地图中返回我的值
If I tried to change the second type with map if I returned my value in the map over
它会打破我所拥有的一切，它不再是 Endo。
it then it would break everything I would have it would not be Endo anymore.
所以它不是函子。
So it is not a functor.
在这之后我必须要谈一件事。
I do have to talk about one thing after this.
不要让我忘记。
Don't let me forget.
[笑] 我们在谈论逆映射和逆变函子。
[LAUGH] We're talking about contra map and contravariant functors.
所以，我们没有关于 Endo 的地图，但我们可以说，就像其他地图一样，我们会
So, we don't have map on Endo, but we can say, just like the other ones we'll
说与 Endo 和 x 而不是同时运行并连接结果。
say with Endo and x instead of running both and concatenate the results.
我将运行另一个，然后用另一个的结果运行我的。
I will run the other one and then run mine with the result of the other one.
凉爽的。我们必须扔掉这个
Cool. We'll have to throw this
在一个小清单 哇。
in a little list Wow.
[笑] .List 来自 immutable js 的列表是扩展和
[LAUGH] .List list from immutable j s are extensions and
我们将向下折叠 Endo，我们没有 Endo.empty，
we'll foldMap down Endo, we don't have Endo.empty,
Endo.empty 会是什么样子？
what would Endo.empty look like?
我们有一个 Endo，下一步是什么？
We have an Endo, what's next?
X 是 Id，这行得通吗？
X be Id, does that work?
那么会发生什么？
So what happens?
[声音] 哦，我要给你看结果，但它也应该说远藤，
[SOUND] Op, and I'm gonna show you the result, but also it should say Endo,
它里面应该有一个字符串，对吧？
it should have a string in it, right?
你这样做吗？
Do you do that?
我们走了。
There we go.
那看起来更好。
That looks better.
[笑] 好的，所以我们有了结果。
[LAUGH] All right, so we have a result.
我们将把地图折叠起来。
And we'll fold map this thing down.
然后我们将运行它。
And then we'll run it.
是的，就在这里。
Yeah, right down here.
我们将控制该日志。
And we'll console that log.
结果。
The result.
不知道如何有效地做到这一点，我们一无所获。
Don't know how to do this efficiently and we get nothing.
天哪，这不好。
Goodness, that's not good.
这里发生了什么事？
What's happening here?
所以原来是空的，我怀疑是我们的问题。
So the original empty, I'm suspecting is our problem.
让我们继续并专注于此。
Let's go ahead and focus on that.
所以它需要一个空字符串原始 Endo 需要一个空字符串。
So it takes an empty string original Endo takes an empty string.
然后当我们在这个东西上运行它时，
And then when we run it on this thing,
我认为它在这里忽略了它的参数，只返回一个空字符串。
I think it ignores its argument right here and just returns an empty string.
所以也许，那是错误的
So perhaps, that was wrong and
我们会说 empty 接受这个，我们会看看那里会发生什么，好吧。
we'll say empty takes this and we'll see what happens there, okay.
这样可行。我必须澄清这一点
That works. I have to clarify this one and
回到你身边，因为我很困惑，但至少它是有效的。
come back to you because I'm getting confused, but at least it's working.
所以这里的重点是我们通过组合将所有这些组合起来。
So the point here is that we're combining all these by composition.
并且我们在我们的内部运行另一个是我们的无关紧要
And it kind of doesn't matter that we're running the other one inside ours are ours
在另一个里面。
inside the other.
就像我们这样做一样。
Like if we did it this way.
顺序有点无关紧要。
The order kinda doesn't matter.
但是然后我们回到我们的空方法，对吗？
But then we go back to our empty method, right?
我们这样做的地方我试图解释这就是为什么 empty 没有参数的原因。
Where we do that I'm trying to make of that's why empty takes no arguments.
这很有意义。
That makes a lot of sense.
我们走了。这样就清楚了。
There we go. So that clears that up.